<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cards>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title><em>Bees!</em></title>
    <description>
      You are swarmed by angry bees. You must run about frantically trying to
      avoid them for the duration.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Shout in terror and run out the nearest exit, screaming about bees. Refuse
      to return until they’ve gone.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>Stoned Out of Your Gourd</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You believe you have been turned to stone. You may not act for the
        duration, nor may you speak.
      </line>
      <line>
        On the positive side, you are immune to many types of damage.
      </line>
    </description>
    <acting>Sit as still as possible without speaking for the duration.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long" example="true">
    <title>Slow Motion</title>
    <description>
      You feel incredibly sluggish. Your movement speed is halved (round down),
      and any bonus actions count as full actions.
    </description>
    <acting>
      <line>Speak to your party <em>very</em> slowly.</line>
      <line>Try to hold elaborate conversations.</line>
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Two Heads Are Not Better</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You have sprouted a second head. It will disagree with you and
        contradict your every thought.
      </line>
      <line>Argue with it. Change your mind on every decision.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Which End Goes Toward the Enemy?</title>
    <description>
      <line>You are constantly distracted to the point of dissociation.</line>
      <line>Do not add your proficiency bonus to any rolls.</line>
    </description>
    <acting>Act distracted and exceptionally clumsy.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Master of the Universe</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        Everyone is your servant. Have them do anything you don’t feel like
        doing.
      </line>
      <line>
        If they resist, ask them why you pay them at all.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>I’ll Bite Yer Kneecaps Off!</title>
    <description>
      <line>You feel rather inferior to your other companions.</line>
      <line>Always pick a fight with the biggest enemy to prove yourself.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Ritual Madness</title>
    <description>
      You’ve suddenly developed a rather strange habit. Every time you roll a
      die, do something strange. You must perform the same action every time you
      roll.
    </description>
    <acting tight="true">
      Sneeze loudly. Point at each die rolled 3 times. Scratch a body part in
      exactly the same place 5 times, counting loudly. Count up to, or down
      from, the number rolled. Check for your wallet.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Rapid Cycling</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        Sometimes you like to think things through. Other times… not so much.
      </line>
      <line>
        Act Lawful for 1d10 minutes, then act Chaotic for 1d10 minutes. Repeat
        for one session.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Three-Ring Circus!</title>
    <description>
      <line>You’re the lead actor of a circus!</line>
      <line>
        Proclaim everything you’re about to do, as if you’re a ringmaster at a
        circus.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long" enabled="false">
    <title>Goodnight!</title>
    <description>
      You fall unconscious for the duration. No amount of jostling or damage can
      wake you.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Safety Found at the Bottom of a Bottle</title>
    <description>
      <line>Your character drinks excessively.</line>
      <line>
        To calm their nerves, to calm their shaking hands, to quiet the voices,
        or to keep the nightmares at bay.
      </line>
      <line>Or any combination of those.</line>
    </description>
    <acting>Act drunk out-of-game.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Five-Finger Discount</title>
    <description>
      If you pick something up, do not give it to your companions. Take any loot
      that drops.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Try to take random items from the other players. Give them back at the end
      of the session if it is not noticed.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Younger Sibling Syndrome</title>
    <description>
      Pick a character in the party. Your character must act like them.
    </description>
    <acting>Behave like the player who belongs to that character.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title shrink="true">I’m Only Interesting If I Tell Tall Tales</title>
    <description>
      <line>Bend the truth, exaggerate, or lie about everything.</line>
      <line>The more audacious the better.</line>
      <line>You have no shame.</line>
    </description>
    <acting>
      Exaggerate everything at the table. Tell as many tall tales as you can.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>My Goal Is All That Matters</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        Endlessly pursue your personal goals regardless of anything else going
        on, or your party’s desires.
      </line>
      <line>This may require going alone.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>What Is the Point?</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        The color has drained from the world. None of your prior interests hold
        any excitement. All of your efforts to are doomed to failure.
      </line>
      <line>
        You have disadvantage on Charisma Ability Checks and Saving Throws.
      </line>
    </description>
    <acting tight="true">
      Speak in a monotone, and appear disinterested in anything going on around
      you.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>My Dad Owns A Dealership!</title>
    <description>
      <line>Everyone is silently judging your actions.</line>
      <line>Accuse them of it! Act upon it!</line>
      <line>Why are they mocking you?</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title shrink="true">I am so beautiful … to me! Can’t you see?</title>
    <description>
      You’re the smartest, strongest, fastest, and most beautiful person you’ve
      ever known.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>They’re Coming to Take Me Away!</title>
    <description>
      There are foes chasing you everywhere you go, and they are watching you.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title shrink="true">Just keep swimming, just keep swimming…</title>
    <description>
      You are compelled to repeat a specific activity over and over.
    </description>
    <acting>Repeat a task out-of-game.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title><em>Look!</em> A Flying Monkey!</title>
    <description>
      You experience vivid hallucinations for the duration, and have
      disadvantage on ability checks.
    </description>
    <acting>Point out strange sightings to your companions.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Jet Fuel Can’t Melt Steel Beams</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You suffer extreme paranoia, seeing conspiracies every where you turn.
      </line>
      <line>
        You have disadvantage on Wisdom and Charisma Ability Checks and Saving
        Throws.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Disgusting! Keep That Away!</title>
    <description>
      You find something (of your choice, but usually the source of your
      madness) incredibly revolting, as if affected by the
      <strong>Antipathy</strong> spell.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title shrink="true">
      Adventuring Under the Influence
    </title>
    <description>
      <line>You experience a powerful delusion.</line>
      <line>
        Discreetly ask your DM for a potion name. You must act as if you are
        under the effects of that potion.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>My, This Must Be Lucky!</title>
    <description>
      You become attached to a non-combat item of your choice. You suffer
      Disadvantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws when over
      30' away from it.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Bring a nonsensical item everywhere with you. Your chair might be a good
      place to start.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>I Can’t Hear! I Can’t See!</title>
    <description>
      Roll a d4. On a 1, you are <strong>Blinded</strong>. Otherwise, you are
      <strong>Deafened</strong>.
    </description>
    <acting>
      If you are Blinded, close your eyes and play blind! If you are Deafened,
      don’t listen to anyone other than the DM.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>“A Boy’s Best Friend Is His Mother”</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You suffer uncontrollable tremors or tics, which pose disadvantage on
        attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws that involve Strength or
        Dexterity.
      </line>
      <line>
        You must also make a Dexterity Saving Throw to cast a spell with
        Somatic components.
      </line>
    </description>
    <acting>Twitch randomly out-of-game.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Who are you? Who, who? Who, who?</title>
    <description>
      You suffer from partial amnesia. You know who you are and retain racial
      traits and class features, but you don’t recognize other people or events
      prior to your madness.
    </description>
    <acting>Act like you do not know the other players.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>The Trouble With Mr. Bean</title>
    <description>
      <line>You have lost your ability to speak.</line>
      <line>This includes Verbal spell components</line>
    </description>
    <acting>
      Resort to exaggerated facial expressions and frustrated signs to get
      points across.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>His Name is Tyler Durden</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        There’s only one person you can trust, and only you can see them.
      </line>
      <line>
        You have an imaginary friend! Communicate with them regularly and ask
        for their advice and opinion.
    </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>This Is Hilarious!</title>
    <description>
      You find it difficult to take anything seriously. The more serious the
      situation, the funnier it is.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>Oh my God, It Even Has a Watermark</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You really like killing people. And you have developed such a knack for
        it.
      </line>
      <line>
        Viciously mutilate your foes and their bodies. Attempt to kill your
        allies.
      </line>
    </description>
    <acting tight="true">
      <line>
        Profess your undying admiration for Huey Lewis and Phil Collins.
      </line>
      <line>
        Pontificate on the quality of that fine Chardonnay you’re not drinking.
      </line>
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Oh. I’m Dead</title>
    <description>
      <line>Act like a ghost.</line>
      <line>Try to pass through walls and scare people.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>You’re the Star!</title>
    <description>
      <line>Sing anything you say.</line>
      <line>Every movement you make must be a grand, flourished gesture.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>The Floor Is Lava</title>
    <description>
      Your character must attempt to avoid the ground, or hop up and down
      frantically.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Don’t touch the floor! (Unless you need to use the restroom. DM’s option
      to award an Inspiration Point if you manage to make it to the restroom
      without touching the floor.)
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>Cut It Out! Mmmmmmoooommmmm!</title>
    <description>
      You must mimic the person to your immediate left.
    </description>
    <acting>
      <line>Mimic everything the person to your left does.</line>
      <line>
        If you are doing something else, you may ignore this rule for that
        period, but your character may not.
      </line>
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title><em>Deep Breathing</em></title>
    <description>
      <line>You must audibly breathe, taking deep breaths and deep exhales.</line>
      <line>
        If you stop for any reason, the walls begin to close upon you. Make a
        Constitution Saving Throw or suffer the effects of asphyxiation.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>Is It Safe to Do That?</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You must ask the DM for permission to do anything for the duration.
      </line>
      <line>Anything.</line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Long">
    <title><em>Banana Hammock!</em></title>
    <description>
      You must shout a random word that you think of every 10 minutes.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short" shrink="true">
    <title>Drove downtown in the rain …</title>
    <description>
      The outside world isn’t safe! Retreat within your mind for safety. You are
      paralyzed for the duration.
    </description>
    <acting>Do not move for the duration.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>That’s <em>Hilarious!</em></title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You are under an effect similar to <strong>Tasha’s Hideous
        Laughter</strong>, but you make the saving throw at the
        <em>beginning</em> of <em>each</em> turn.
     </line>
      <line>
        You may act only if you succeed, otherwise you are incapacitated by
        laughter.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short" example="true">
    <title>Zoiks!</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        You’re terrified of demons. And spiders. And people. And that rock over
        there.
      </line>
      <line>Pretty much everything.</line>
      <line>You are <strong>Frightened</strong> for the duration.</line>
    </description>
    <acting>Jump in fear (and maybe shout too!) if someone acknowledges you.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>Ĉu Vi Povas Kompreni Min?</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        What language did you speak? You’ve forgotten. Time to make a new
        language.
      </line>
      <line>
        You are incapable of normal speech (including casting spells that
        require Verbal components) for the duration, and can only babble
        incoherently.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>Enemies Are All Around! It’s Not Safe!</title>
    <description>
      Attack the nearest creature, friend or foe (choose randomly if more than
      one creature qualifies) each round for the duration.
    </description>
    <acting>Pretend the other players are monsters or evil villains.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title><em>Look!</em> A Flying Monkey!</title>
    <description>
      You experience vivid hallucinations for the duration, and have
      disadvantage on ability checks.
    </description>
    <acting>Point out strange sightings to your companions.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>You are Getting Sleepy …</title>
    <description>
      You will do whatever anyone tells you that isn’t obviously self-
      destructive for the duration.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Do what you are told out-of-game as well, as long as it’s not harmful.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>That Looks Rather Tasty…</title>
    <description>
      For the duration, you have an all-consuming urge to eat something strange,
      such as dirt or slime for the duration.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Ask the player next to you if you can eat their pencil, or dice, or
      character sheet.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short" enabled="false">
    <title>Goodnight!</title>
    <description>You fall unconscious for the duration.</description>
    <acting>Slump over on the table, unresponsive.</acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>It Sounds Like Truncheons &amp; Flagons</title>
    <description>
      <line>
        We are just pawns in a game of giants! They leave our fates up to the
        dice! Look above you! Do you not see them?
      </line>
      <line>
        You are convinced that this is just a tabletop game played by giant
        people.
      </line>
    </description>
  </card>
  <!-- Mine -->
  <card duration="Long">
    <title>It Puts the Lotion on the Skin</title>
    <description>
      You keep trophies of your vanquished enemies and turn them into
      adornments.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Keep dice that rolled well as trophies. Try to collect both yours and
      others.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite" example="true">
    <title>A Nice Chianti</title>
    <description>
      The flesh of intelligent creatures is delicious! You feel an
      overwhelming urge to eat them. Your enemies are the ideal meal, but your
      compatriots will do in a pinch.
    </description>
    <acting>
      How long can you go before the table realizes it’s a Hannibal Lecter
      impression?
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>The Strange Eden of the Hyborian Age</title>
    <description>
      You degenerate into beastly behavior, seeming more like a wild animal than
      a thinking being. You lose higher-order skills and abilities, and are only
      able to make raw Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution checks without
      proficiency.
    </description>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>With a Halo of Singing Birds</title>
    <description>
      When you take damage, you must make a Wisdom Saving Throw, or suffer
      effects similar to a Confusion spell, lasting 1 minute.
    </description>
    <acting>
      When anyone touches you, your character sheet, dice, or any other
      possessions, act disoriented and confused.
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Short">
    <title>They’re After Me Lucky Charms!</title>
    <description>
      Everyone wants to steal your belongings. You get violent if anyone
      touches anything belonging to you.
    </description>
    <acting>
      Accuse anyone who touches your stuff of trying to steal it. Be liberal
      with the definition of “your stuff.”
    </acting>
  </card>
  <card duration="Indefinite">
    <title>(Wo)Man of La Mancha</title>
    <description>
      You are granted a vision showing you the way out your larger predicament
      for you and your compatriots. Anyone who disagrees or says otherwise is
      intentionally misleading you, and your new flock.
    </description>
  </card>
</cards>
